<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

<channel>
<title>Glen's Blog</title>
<intro>Talks about everything</intro>
<copyright>Glen owns it</copyright>
<language>en-us</language>
<link>https://glen-programmer.github.io/glen-home/rss.xml</link>
<atom:link href="https://glen-programmer.github.io/glen-home/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

<item>
<title>Productivity Being the Modern BS</title>
<pubDate>Sat 02 May 2020 10:00:00 PM</pubDate>
<description>
  <![CDATA[
    <p>
      Hugely influenced and inspired by
      <a href="https://invidio.us/watch?v=eVwW6Jq3_TE">Our Productivity Obsession</a>
    </p>
    <h3>Productivity takes root from a set of Assumptions</h3>
    <ul>
      <li>Being more productive improve quality of life</li>
      <li>Some random dudes from the internet know how to make you
	productive</li>
      <li>You don't know how to be productive</li>
    </ul>

    <p>Productivity-related materials, despite being in multiple
      forms: videos, podcasts, written words, can be categorized into
      2 main groups based on their 'natures'.</p>
    <ol>
      <li>Motivational materials</li>
      <li>Informative materials</li>
    </ol>
    <p>And we shall discuss their flaws one by one</p>

    <h3>To do xyz, first you need to be motivated</h3>
    <p>If you have achieved anything, naming those insignificant ones, such
    as throwing the rubbish in the nearby recycling station, you
    normally know how to repeat your actions(ofc). For those actions that
    we carried out routinely, we form habits out of it. We don't need
    motivation to do those.</p>
    <p>For more difficult tasks, naming those you don't perceive them
    as entertainment, non-routines, you need to have good
    justification for yourself to do these tasks. If you know it is
    important and urgent, you might just do it in order to avoid
    consequences. However, for those without clear deadlines,
    reaching a higher level of 'Activational Energy' become much
    difficult.</p>
    <p>It is alright though, since the stuff that need to be done,
    should be done naturally one way or another. Not for those cannot
    be done, however.</p>
    <p>xyz need motivational videos, since he</p>
    <ol>
      <li>Doesn't have the 'Activational Energy' required to do abc</li>
      <li>Doesn't have good causes for doing abc</li>
      <li>Doesn't think it is important and urgent to do abc</li>
      <li>Doesn't think abc could be done unless you are 'better'</li>
    </ol>
    <p>No motivational videos are featuring the current you, they are
    featuring the people who are 'better', more educated, more
    insightful, richer, stronger, or simply more angry.</p>
    <p>By opting for lays down and watches that gray-scale video until
    Uncle Gary finished his speech, you truly believe that you can be
    'better' or having more 'willpowers' to do xyz, to a degree that
    the lost hours that you tore your hearts off, can easily be
    compensated by the future you working harder than ever.</p>
    <p>Right?</p>

    <h3>Someone else knows me better</h3>
    <p>Of course this is sometimes the case. Being a extremely
    subjective entity, a person could not see his flaws easily. That's
    why we need to 'be an observer', judging ourself in a objective
    manner.(ofc again)</p>
    <p>It's easily the case when someone, especially those acclaimed
    figures, to be more objectively productive than you or to be more
    knowledgeable than you. By opting for lays down and watches that
    animated drawing video with cringy cartoon, you truly believe that
    you can learn something you don't already know about
    'productivity' and 'working hard', and you wholeheartedly believe
    that the morning-routine of anut Michelle can be copied roughly to
    fit your lifestyle and quirks. (Let's us at least assume that what 
    they tell you is real and those rituals are actually productive.) </p>
    <p>More than nothing huh?</p>

    <h3>This is just a start</h3>
    <p>It is not your faults evolving from binge-watching-netflix
    normie to binge-watching-youtube chad. No one could give you
    gold nuggets if they don't have any, not one could have any gold
    nuggets unless there is a magical gold mine in San Francisco.</p>

    <h3>Why do they put out those contents?</h3>
    <ol>
      <li>Frick yes, I just learnt from personal experience that doing
      abc is better than doing xyz</li>
      <li>I just want to be somewhat influential and successful</li>
      <li>People like these types of contents, so I make them, and I
      could sell my merch, books, online courses whatever</li>
    </ol>
    <p>Undoubtedly, our lovely economy awards those people who create
    viral contents monetarily. Those full of rhetorics, competitive
    'content-creators' could lose their market values easily, and
    that's basically their motivation and incentive behind all of the
    works they devoted their time to.</p>
    <p>The business model of productivity contents boils down to
    acquiring your time and attention, give you some seemingly great
    contents so that you feel good about yourself, then rip the poop
    out of you by selling stuff and hosting VPNs' ads. Such business model
    fuels their gut to constantly create 'better' videos to buy their 
    groceries and pay for Youtube Premium.</p>
    <p>To the consumers, it is a bad news. Since what you perfer
    is 'one-video-to-rule-them-all', not the daily update on
    'how-to-be-productive-for-the-next-2-hours'. The more time and
    money you spend on contents, more you may be lucky enough to hear
    something astounding, at the same time more addicted to nonsense
    and less time for actually doing 'the work'.</p>

    <h3>I don't trust you, don't forget you are also just a random guy from
    the internet, who may be writing this for ill purposes. And you
    have poor grammar.</h3>
    <p>You shouldn't all of what I just said and my grammar is poor.
    But at least you could learn some Economics101.</p>
    <p>Opportunity Cost is defined as the highest-valued option
      forgone.</p>
    <p>Opportunity Cost = Time Cost + Money Cost.</p>
    <p>When you are watching the same productivity video over and over
    again, be sure to have nothing more valuable to do.</p>
    <p>Notorious Law of DMR - Diminishing Marginal Returns states that
    as you increase the some means of production(in this case, time),
    the output of a production process decreases.</p>
    <p>Just think of it as: more stuff you consooooomed, less stuff
      you get.</p>
    <p>Ok you shall close this tab now.(by RSS Gang)</p>
  ]]>
</description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
